Guide to the George Alfred Kiersch papers, 1991-1999.
Kiersch, George Alfred papers, 1991-1999
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George Alfred Kiersch papers, 1991-1999.
16-14-3181
George A. Kiersch, 1918-
50 cubic ft.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reprints from "The Heritage of Engineering Geology: The First Hundred Years," 1991; "The Expert Witness and Litigation," in the Bulletin of the Association of Engineering Geologists, 1993; and "Engineering geosciences and military operations," in Engineering Geology, 1998.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Emeritus of Geological Sciences, Cornell University.
George A. Kiersch received a B.S. from the Colorado School of Mines, and a Ph.D. from the University of Arizona. As well as teaching at Cornell, he worked as a geologist and exploration manager for industrial firms and government agencies and as a national and international consultant.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reprints from "The Heritage of Engineering Geology: The First Hundred Years," 1991; "The Expert Witness and Litigation," in the Bulletin of the Association of Engineering Geologists, 1993; and "Engineering geosciences and military operations," in Engineering Geology, 1998.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kiersch, George A.,1918-
Subjects:
Engineering geology--History.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Professional Organizations
Textbooks
Private Reports
Court Documents
Course Material
Maps
Photographs
Bound Works
CONTAINER LIST
- Conferences, symposia, professional association meetings; Correspondence, academic papers, newsletters, adgendas; 1987-1996 (Box 1)
- Drilling, exploratory geology; Studies and reports on drilling; correspondence relating to the sale of drilling equipment; course materials; 1966-1975 (Box 2)
- Published Works Academic and Professional; Manuscripts, correspondece, journals, newsletters; 1959-1996 (Box 3)
- Education engineering geology- methods, content, demand for; Journals, manuscripts, course materials (Box 4)
- Possibly Chapters from Geothermal steam: origin, characteristics, occurrence, and exploitation (Box 5)
- The Heritage of Engineering Geology; Notes, manuscripts, corespondence with contributers, publishers, reviewers (Box 6)
- Chapter from ??? (Box 7)
- "Chapters from a proposed textbook ""Engineering Geology"" 1984? (Box 8)
- "Chapters for Geology Lab Manual; Chapter for Textbook ""Engineering Geology Text"" other materials may have been used to produce drafts of these books" (Box 9)
  - Folder labeled Engineering Geology Book Ch 4 Stresses, 1984-1984 (Box 9)
    "Drafts of chapters 3 and 4. Annotations show where chapter headings and numbers had changed from an earlier version of textbook ""Engineering Geology Practice"""
    Chapter Files
  - Cont. from above (Box 9)
    "Outlines for both text books ""Engineering Geology"" and Engineering Geology Practice"""
  - Chapter 5 from ??? Mapping, March 8, 1983 (Box 9)
    "Cover is marked OSHA or Another Agency 'Manual"" For AWH '81-'82. Note on first page reads ""JK - This is a private copy unknow to Profession - Thanks GAK"""
  - Recommendations On Site Investigations Techniques, July 1975 (Box 9)
    Report published by the International Society for Rock Mechanics, Commission On Recommendations On Site Investigations Techniques
    Professional Orgs.
  - Suggested Methods for Geophysical Logging of Boreholes, 1981 (Box 9)
    Report published by the International Society for Rock Mechanics, Commission On Standardization of Laboratory and Field Tests
  - Suggested Method For Petrographic Description of Rocks - Committee On Laboratory Tests Document No. 6, March 1977 (Box 9)
  - Folder SPCo Hdbk - 1959 Some Sections for Engineering Geology Text, 1959-1960 (Box 9)
    Typescript- General Guides for Diagrammic Representation of Rock - Stratigraphic Unites 1959; Letter from GAK to Warren L. Coonrad April 18, 1960
  - Cont. from above (Box 9)
    Typescript with transparencies. PART C Field Observations, Records and Useful Techniques
  - National Environmental Enforcement Journal Vol. 2 No. 3, March 1987 (Box 9)
    Publicatoin of the National Association of Attorneys General
  - Engineering Geology Office Manual - Basic Concepts and Procedures, April 1988 (Box 9)
    US Department of the Interior
  - Environmental Courses, Conferences and Workshops, 1991 (Box 9)
    Catalog from Executive Enterprises Inc
  - Expense list for replacing mailbox destroyed by cable company (Box 9)
    Personal
  - Curriculum Vitae of Jeffrey R. Keaton, October 1987 (Box 9)
  - Photocopies of Appendices for a Text? (Box 9)
  - Folder Part C Automatic Dip? (Box 9)
    Transperancies and Typescript-
  - "Copies of Chapters from ""Environmental Geology Practical Exercises by Bernard W. Pipkin and David Cummings" (Box 9)
    Copy of index and some chapters
  - Folder - Course Outlines Cornell, 1967-1971 (Box 9)
    Course Materials
  - Course Outline and Lab No. 1, September 1967 (Box 9)
  - Several Letters between GAK and Jeffrey Keaton, 1988-1989 (Box 9)
    RE: engineering geology text
  - Several Lab Exercises from Cornell courses (Box 9)
  - The Geology Publisher, 1991 (Box 9)
    Macmillan publishing catalog
  - Folder - Kendall Hunt 1996 Publ -Lab Manual, 1990 (Box 9)
    Correspondence, photocopies, course materials. All for use in preparing the Lab Manual or Exercise Manual
  - Kendall / Hunt Publishing Company Catalog, 1990 (Box 9)
- Chapter from ???; Publications; Vaiont Slide; Course outlines (Box 10)
- Chapters??? Graphics; Photos; Research; Clippings (Box 11)
- Chapters???- Folders; Clippings, Publications (Box 12)
- 4 Drawer cabinet containing slides (Box 13)
- Boxes of slided, some marked with chapter numbers; audio cassettes; audio reel, small slide projector (Box 14)
- Slides; audio tapes; microphone (Box 14A)
- Chapter Folders for ??? (Box 14 (?))
- Overhead projector slides marked PRWICA? Nuclear 1971-1972; 4 drawer cabinet with slides, some glass (Box 15)
- Photos-prints, lsides, negs. 1950s and 1960s (Box 16)
- Photos; microfilm; microscope slides with specimens (Box 16A)
- "Cornell MS and PhD Theses 1969-1971; 1 copy ea. of ""Heritage..."" and Centennial Field Guide, both unwrapped" (Box 17)
- Maps, Cert. Of Frank Laverty P.E.; Pubs- Navajo, others some in German; Folders with photocopies (Box 18)
- Slides and photos (Box 21)
- Maps, Photos, Reports (Box 22)
- Course materials (Box 22 (?))
- Publications (Box 22A)
- Needs a closer look, mixed files (Box 23)
- Publications, lots of Navajo (Box 24)
- Slides (Box 26)
- Slides in a tin box (Box 26A)
- Mixed files - research for a report; Correspondence; Clippings (Box 27)
- AEG Files (Box 28)
- Paper and Spiral bound publications (Box 29)
- Drafts, Publications, Maps (Box 29A)
- Paper bound publications (Box 30)
- SA45 (Box 31)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research; Plastic spiral bound reports (Box 32)
- Publications; Maps (Box 33)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research (Box 34)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research; Supplements to bound volumes-Maps (Box 35)
- Publications. Including Cornell publs; Mineral resources, Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations (Box 36)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research (Box 37)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research (Box 38)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research (Box 39)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research (Box 40)
- Publications and reasearch notes; All possibly for chapters (Box 41)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research; Folder of Loose photocopies (Box 42)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research; Loose photocopies (Box 43)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research (Box 44)
- Bound Volumes of GAK's Reports and Research (Box 45)
- Course Materials (Box 46 (1))
- Course Materials - Illustrations, papers, reports; Maps; Engineering Geology textbook materials - appendices, foreword/intro (Box 47 (2))
- Course Materials; Legas cases; slides; Handbook for Geologists (Box 48 (3))
- Slides; Materials for Publications and Abstracts meant to be bound; slides for legal cases (Box 49 (4))
- Material to be bound - legal cases (Box 50 (5))
- Reports; Legal material - slides. All meant to be bound (Box 51 (6))
- Some course material; Legal docs (Box 52 (7))
- Mostly Course Material; photos; some reports (Box 53 (8))
- Photos; Book plates and Block for book plates (Box 54)
- Undescribed (Box 38 Folder)
  Folder in Box 38
- Unprocssed (Box UN)
- Unprocssed (Box UN)
- Unprocssed (Box UN)